Contact

Uralska 56 +(38160) 02175-73 (Home) nikola.bozic.bg@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-bozic-6328a060 (LinkedIn)

nikolabozicbg.github.io/ nnikolabozic.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Android Development Web Development

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Nikola Bozic

Web Developer, Android Developer

Summary

Talented, hard working and reliable Web and Android Developer with a strong willingness to learn. Able to work well independently or as part of a professional computer program development team. Self-motivated, creative, open-minded and loyal.

Core skills

In depth knowledge of programming Android applications

Solid understanding of JavaScript and Angular 2+

Knowledge of REST API, JSON, XML, Swagger using Jhipster, Spring and Hibernate

Profound knowledge of front-end web development and design using HTML5, CSS3, CSS preprocessor SASS, and Bootstrap.

Experience with using Version Control systems such as Github, Bitbucket

Proficiency in interacting with clients and understanding and translating requirements to technical specifications

Excellent communication, planning and time management skills.

Work Experience

Spear Consulting - Web Application Developer , Android Developer, Belgrade

(April 2018 - Present)

Responsibilities

- Worked as a front end developer using AngularJS JavaScript framework.
- Create d a RESTful Web API service using Spring Boot, Hibernate to generate data which was then consumed in the frontend by AngularJS.
- Develop the front-end components using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap , and AngularJS.
- Used Swagger to test Web API Functionality
- Worked on Android Applications

Zlatiborac - Android Developer, Belgrade

(January 2018 - April 2018)

Responsibilities

- Designed and built advanced applications for sales on Android platform
- Implementation of RESTful APIs(Oauth 2.0, Http Interceptor)
 Client with Retrofit to pull server data
- Synchronize data to SQLlite using Room ORM
- Implemented Software Architecture structure pattern (Model-View-ViewModel) and Android Architecture Components (Live Data View Model)
- Developed UI components using Constraint Layout

Digit Group - Android Developer, Belgrade

(June 2016 - January 2018)

Responsibilities

Working on communication between Android application and fiscal printer

Freelance - Android Developer, Belgrade

(June 2016 – June 2017)

Responsibilities

- Developed Android application "Auto Magazin" for newspaper magazine about cars
- Developed "Skolarac" Android application for student timesheet and grade tracking

Education

Machine engineering school "Radoje Dakić" Belgrade - department of robotics

Faculty of Sport and Physical Education University of Belgrade,

School of Modern business - Java Basic Coruse

Advance Tech Solutions & Softline - Java Advanced Course

Advance Tech Solutions & Softline - Android developer course